Guide to WXCI Records RG.5.15.2
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
WXCI Records
1972-2009
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
WXCI
McCarney, Hugh
RG.5.15.2
188
1 Linear Feet, 1 box
Documentation of WXCI's operation dating back to 1972. Collection includes correspondence between WXCI staff members with University administration, membership and outside vendors. Compiled from the files of WXCI faculty advisor, Dr. Hugh McCarney.
Biographical / Historical
WXCI (91.7 FM) is a student radio station broadcasting at 3,000 watts with a stereo transmitter. Studios are located at WCSU's Midtown Campus and the transmitter is located at the Westside campus. It also streams its broadcasts on the Web. The radio station obtained its FCC license to operate on 28 February 1973. Student Rob Abbett nickname Rabbett was the first DJ to broadcast at 10 Watts of power. Prior to the formation of WXCI, a student club operated an AM carrier current system in dorms and campus buildings under the call letters: WCST. WCST was launched by Bob Wilson in 1968. WXCI was, as of 2008, the second largest college radio station in CT at 3000 watts. The station is primarily funded through student activity fees but also derives support from the WCSU Alumni Association and grants. WXCI was an early platform for alternative music in the 1980s.
Scope and Contents
Contains early records and by-laws of the Campus Broadcast Association which became WXCI. Documents are arranged by year, and divided into correspondence and operational documents. Some of the operational documents include, emergency broadcast system guidelines, lists of student members, playlists, and financial statements.
Photographs are separated and collocated in their own series.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically by academic year.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Radio stations -- Connecticut.; McCarney, Hugh; Western Connecticut State University. Student Government Association.; Western Connecticut State University. Office of Alumni Affairs
- Administrative, 57631
  - 1973-1977 Correspondence, 57632 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Materials about the founding of WXCI.
  - 1972-1977 Operational, 57635 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Clippings and materials regarding the founding of WXCI
  - Praise and Awards, 1977-1992 (Box 1, Folder 2.1)
    Positive correspondence, certificates, and awards from various organizations
  - 1977-1978 Correspondences, 57634; 1 Linear Feet (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1977-1978 Operational, 57636 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1978-1979 Correspondence, 57637 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Ed Struski, Richard Reimold, Dood.
  - 1978-1979 Operational, 57638 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1979-1980 Correspondence, 57639 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Bruce Goldsen, Dave Landry, Ed Struski, Bill Jacquemin, Carl Mearman, Chip Grant, Pete Pap, Paul Johnson
  - 1979-1980 Operational, 57640 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Campus Broadcast Association bylaws, expenditures, etc.
  - 1979-1980 Playlists, 57641 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1980-1981 Correspondence, 57642 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Bruce Goldsen, Donald Thoren, Ron McDonald (sermons?)
  - 1981-1982 Correspondence, 1980-1981; 57643 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    L. Russell Watjen, Bill Erikson, Diana Perri, Donald Thoren
  - 1981-1982 Operational, 57644 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Equipment inventory, WXCI Bylaws, Members List, etc.
  - 1982-1983 Correspondence, 57645 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Sue Szanti, Michael Sylvia, The Spoons, drinking age
  - 1982-1983 Operational, 57646 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Donald Thoren, Executive Board, Operational Board, equipment inventory
  - 1983-1984 Correspondence and operational, 57647 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Jim Pegolotti, Donald Thoren, equipment inventory,, club constitution
  - 1984-1985 Correspondence, 57648 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Scott Brunjes, Thomas Porter, Darrell Ohrt, Russell Watjen, "Morning Sickness" program
  - 1984-1985 Operational, 57649 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Waterbury Republican articles on WXCI and DJ Bill Baker "Morning Sickness", Arbitron ratings for Danbury
  - 1985-1986 Correspondence, 57650 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Bill Baker, "Morning Sickness"
  - 1985-1986 Operational, 57651 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Arbitron reports on Danbury region, equipment inventory
  - 1986-1987 Correspondence, 57652 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Arbitron estimates, Tom Church, Morgan Williams, Joan Apple Lemoine, Robert Kaufman
  - 1986-1987 Operational, 57653 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Arbitron ratings, equipment inventory
  - 1987-1988 Correspondence, 57654 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    WXCI member break-in, Rich Sullivan, Fire Code violations and payments, Stephen Feldman, Cindy Winters, Morgan Williams, CMJ
  - 1987-1988 Operational, 57655 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Suggestions and comments from the staff regarding operations, minutes, members list, policies and proceedures, equipment list
  - 1988-1989 Correspondence, 57656 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Anne Corey, Gale Alexander, Troy Canton, Patty Grannon, Chuck Bergen
  - 1988-1989 Operational, 57657 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Arbitron ratings, operations reports, program proposals, minutes, accounting
  - 1990-1991 Correspondence, 57658 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Cynthia Cherniske, Debbie Donais, Don Destafano
  - 1990-1991 Operational, 57659 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Members list, transmitter electrical costs, transmitter wiring
  - FCC Permits, 1990-1996 (Box 1, Folder 27.1)
    Federal Communication Commission
  - 1991-1992 Correspondence, 57660 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Stephen Gerhard
  - 1991-1992 Operational, 57661 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Minutes, list of jocks, floor plan
  - General Manager, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 29.1)
    Folder contains correspondence (including letters regarding interference between WOSR and WXCI) and memoranda.
  - 1992-1993 Correspondence, 57662 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Joan Macko, Donald DeStefano, Richard Sullivan, Milissa Wassik
  - 1992-1993 Operational, 57663 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Flyer, Minutes, membership, Darryl Ohrt, floor plan, clipping, arbitron ratings, budget
  - General Manager, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 31.1)
    Folder includes general manager's correspondence, minutes of board meetings, newsletters, etc.
  - 1993-1994 Correspondence, 57664 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Richard Sullivan, Chris Nolan, Kevin Haddad
  - 1993-1994 Operational, 57665 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Minutes, forms, calendar, agenda, map of westside, tower license agreement
    Separated Materials
    Materials presumably for the 20th anniversary were transferred to folders 1 and 2.
  - General Manager, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 33.1)
    Folder includes general manager's correspondence, minutes, agendas, operating log violation reports, and indecency policy notes.
  - 1994-1995 Correspondence, 57666 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Kevin Haddad, Chris Nolan, Bruce Bellucci, Nancy Griffin, notes regarding new transmitter tower and equipment purchase.
  - 1994-1995 Operational, 57667 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Agenda, minutes, equipment wishlist, programming guide, College Radio Awards, primer on decency, floorplan
  - 1995-1996 Correspondence and Operational documents, 57668 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Kevin Haddad, Chris Nolan, Staff List, log
  - 1996-1997 Correspondence, 57669 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Todd Mabe, Tom Deloge, transmitter, equipment inventory
  - 1996-1997 Operational, 57670 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Blueprint for new signal tower, signal map, diagrams
  - 1997-1998 Correspondence, 57672 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Controversy over funding of a P.H.A.T event with the Black Student Alliance (BSA), Afena Cobham, Bryan Halcott, Rodney Riley, Marcia Kendall
  - 1997-1998 Operational, 57673 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Budgets, floorplan
  - 1998-1999 Correspondence and operational, 57674 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Clipping, William Reppucci, Brian Halcott, Amy Foster
  - 1999-2000 Correspondence, 57675 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Baker and Hostetler, Richard Sullivan, FCC Registration for antenna tower, FAA Registration
  - 1999-2000 Operational, 57676 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Budget, "Shout Brother Shout", Broadcast and Cable Initial Election Statement
  - 2000-2001 Operational, 57680 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Agendas, minutes, invoices, budget
  - 2000-2001 Correspondence, 57679 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Amy Thurston, Paul Popeski, Mike Epps, Adeline Gronkowski, Thomas Feola
  - General Manager, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 45.1)
    Folder contains correspondence, general manager refrence guides, operations board by-laws, broadcast agreement, etc.
  - 2001-2002 Correspondence, 57677 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Dan Sterling, Keenon Snell, Kevin Mason, Laura-Leigh Wilcox, Nancy London
  - 2001-2002 Operational, 57678 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    Agendas, minutes, clippings, Hard Attack, Connecticut Broadcasters Association, antenna tower, SESAC, indecency policy
  - 2002-2003 Correspondence and operational, 57681 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Agenda, CBA
  - 2003-2004 Correspondence, 57682 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Cecilia M. G. Martins, Kenneth Howard, Jeffrey Maccarone, Patrick Carlone
  - 2003-2004 Operational, 57683 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Agenda, AP and PA agreements
  - 2004-2005 Correspondence, 57684 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Rf Licensing, Com Search, Alumni Association
  - 2004-2005 Operational, 57685 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    Minutes, agenda, IBS, financial
  - Life Member Offer of Service, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 52.1)
  - 2005-2006 Correspondence, 57686 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    Mark Case, Citadel Broadcasting Company, Comsearch
  - 2005-2006 Operational, 57687 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Agenda, Minutes, personal service agreement, FCC renewal form
  - 2006-2007 Correspondence and Operational, 57689 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Micronet, John Selwyn, Minutes, Agenda, Harry Rinker, financial
  - 2006-2007 Correspondence and Operational, 57690 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - 2007-2008 Correspondence and Operational, 57691 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Agenda, Minutes, AP agreement, ratings, clippings
  - 2008-2009 Correspondence and Operational, 57692 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    Agenda, Minutes, clippings, Comsearch, Justin Mazzarese,
- Photographs and Miscellanea, 1978-2004; 57693
  - Staff Photo, 1978; 57695 (Box 1, Folder 1A)
    1 3.5x5" color
  - Staff photos, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1A)
    4 8x10" black and white
  - DJ Portraits, 1990-2005; 57694 (Box 1, Folder 1A)
    11, 4x4", black and white; 1, 3.5x5, black and white of Scott Brunjes.
  - General Photographs, 1980-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1B)
    8 3.5x4.4" 14 3.5x4.9" 2 3.5x5.1" color photographs 1 4x5" 8 4x6" color 2 4x6" black and white 8 5x7" 9 negative strips with images of the WXCI station and antenna
  - Newspaper clippings, 1980-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1C)
  - Rolling Stone, 1986; 58665 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Article on WXCI page 84
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Gift of Patrick Shea
  - Press Passes, undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
    Originally in the Publications and Design Department files.
  - Engineering Test, Training and Forms, undated (Box 1, Folder 59.1)
  - History, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 59.2)
  - 35th Celebration, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 59.3)
    Reservation slips, speech
  - 25th Celebration, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 59.4)
    Planning documents, attendance, memoranda
  - News Blimp (reels), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 60-61)
    Two reels of the Progressive Radio Network's program (produced in the Bronx in NYC): Radio Blimp. ~45mins each. Somewhat humerous takes on light news stories punctuated with music.
  - T-shirts and Promotional Items, circa 1980-2000 (Box OS1, Item 1-8)
    Includes 10 t-shirts including commemorative 20th reunion t-shirt, bottle opener
  - PSA Reel-to-Reel, 1977-1980 (Box OS1, Item 9-10)
    2 Reels Broadcasting Foundation of America, International Almanac #924 Israel Television Advertising for Children: Buy it or Ban it